准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
愚者生存
导演
分镜
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
好耶  我们要去珊迪家
All right, we're going to Sandy's house
我要比你先到
I'm going to beat you there
给树捂热乎点  珊迪
Keep the tree warm, Sandy
禁止入内
珊迪
Sandy?
Hey, Sandy
干嘛挂牌子
what's with the sign
你看  她上美食频道了
Look, she's on The Eating Channel
你好
Howdy
如果你看到了这个
If y'all are watching this
这就表示我过冬睡着了
that means I'm asleep for the winter
此时的睡眠就叫做冬眠
This sleep is called hibernation
冬眠
冬眠期间
During hibernation
动物们都很不愿意突然被吵醒
animals don't like to be woken up
所以请勿打扰
So do not disturb
说的就是你  海绵宝宝
That means you, SpongeBob
最好戴上
We better put these on
不必了  派大星
Never mind, Pat
珊迪说不要进去
Sandy said not to come in
排水
我们还是开溜吧
Let's amscray
你什么时候才学得会  海绵宝宝
When are you going to learn, SpongeBob?
不的意思就是  是
"No" means "yes"
派大星  跟你说
Patrick, listen
得多少次才能
how many times do we have to
海绵宝宝  你看这个
SpongeBob, look at this
这什么东西
What is this stuff?
是辽阔梦幻的仙境
It's a vast, swirling wonderland
充满洁白闪耀的好景
of sparkling white pleasure
来充实你的感官
Let it fill your senses
尽享层层叠叠  松软如枕的舒爽
with cascading, fluffy pillows
of excitement and comfort
体验从未有过的怡情
as you've never felt before
哇  派大星
Wow, Patrick
好文采
That was beautiful
什么
What?
我刚在念这张糖果包装纸  你看
I was just reading this candy wrapper, see?
派大星
Patrick
把头盔戴回去
Put your helmet back on
珊迪家里没有水
You know there's no water at Sandy's house
没事  海绵宝宝
It's okay, SpongeBob
这东西就是水
This stuff is water
你看
Look
看来你说的对
I guess you're right
脱掉不会有事
It's okay here
脱掉吧
Take it off
没人看的
No one's looking
海绵宝宝  你听见没
SpongeBob, did you hear that?
应该是从珊迪的树里面传来的
I think it came from up in Sandy's tree
好一棵累垮的树
That is one tired tree
去看一下
Let's check it out
看看珊迪的床上有什么
Look what's in Sandy's bed
像个充了太多气的珊迪娃娃
Looks like an overinflated Sandy doll
这东西好像就是珊迪
I think this thing is Sandy
冬眠一定就是
Hibernation must mean
美容觉的反义词
the opposite of beauty sleep
我已经受够你肮脏的勾当了  坏蛋丹
I've had enough of your dastardly deeds, Dirty Dan
我要逮到你和你同伙  钉子头拉里
I'm gonna get you and your partner, Pinhead Larry
不然我就不叫
or my name ain't
警长珊迪
Sheriff Sandy
她一定是梦见了德克萨斯的罪犯
She must be dreaming about Texas outlaws
小心  珊迪
Look out, Sandy
我是坏蛋丹
I'm Dirty Dan
我要逮到你
I'm gonna catch you
用纳税人的钱把你关进牢里
and throw in jail at taxpayers' expense
最好跑快点  珊迪
You better run faster, Sandy
对  我就快逃走了
Yeah, I'm getting away
跑快点
Run faster
快啊  我们就快上出租车了
Hurry, we're getting in a taxi
快点  快点
Faster, faster
我要逮到你们两个
I'll get you two
你们就是纯粹的邪恶化身
You're nothing but pure evil
就跟报纸上的漫画一个样
Just like newspaper comics
走了  派大星
Come on, Patrick
别再打扰人家了
We shouldn't disturb her anymore
那不叫打扰
That's not disturbing
这才叫打扰
This is disturbing
膈 应
你好啊  海绵宝宝
Hi, there, SpongeBob
我叫派大背
My name is Patback
确实看着就膈应
That is really disturbing
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
跑快点  海绵宝宝
Faster, SpongeBob
她快追上我们了
She's gaining on us
珊迪  不要
Sandy, no
住手
Stop
我警告过你了  坏蛋丹
I warned you, Dirty Dan
现在你要被我狠狠揍一顿
Now you just crossed the border into Hurtville
珊迪  是我们
Sandy, it's us
你朋友海绵宝宝和派大星
your friends SpongeBob and Patrick
求你了  珊迪
Please, Sandy
我没钱去干洗
I can't afford dry cleaning
我要剥了你们皮  做成六码的靴子
Gonna skin ya and make a pair of size six boots
玩完了
Fun's over
绝对不能又把她吵醒了
We sure don't want to wake her up again
可惜我们身上
Too bad we don't have
没有耳塞可以帮她戴上
any earplugs to put on her
我就只有肚脐眼里面的绒毛
Yeah, all's I got is this belly button lint
好啊  派大星
All right, Pat
我要扒了你们胳膊
I'm gonna rip your arms off
还有煎饼
and flapjacks
这样应该就行了
Well, that ought to work
珊迪  有没有用
Hey, Sandy, does it work?
珊迪  如果听不见
Hey, Sandy, if you can't hear us
就别说话
don't say anything
珊迪
Hey, Sandy
别醒了
Don't wake up
再见  警长珊迪
See you later, Sheriff Sandy
你被捕了
You're under arrest
你逮不到我的
You'll never catch me
这样不公平
That's not fair
牛仔可买不起大炮
Cowboys couldn't afford cannons
牛仔也买不起客货两用车
They couldn't afford station wagons, either
车身面板不错
Nice paneling
好了  钉子头
All right, Pinhead
你的死期到了
Your time is up
你叫谁钉子头
Who you calling Pinhead?
我要当坏蛋丹
I want to be Dirty Dan
你凭什么觉得你能当坏蛋丹
What makes you think you can be Dirty Dan?
我又坏又脏
I'm dirty
我才是坏蛋丹
I'd say I'm Dirty Dan
我是坏蛋丹
I'm Dirty Dan
大喊大叫会害你没
Screaming will get you no
你们两个谁才是坏蛋丹
Which one of you fellers is the real Dirty Dan?
我是
I am
派大星
Patrick
辣鸡翅
Hot wings
好  钉子头拉里
Okay, Pinhead Larry
到你受死了
Now you get yours
钉子头
Pinhead
你要为你犯的罪付出代价  钉子头
Now you're gonna pay for those crimes, Pinhead
珊迪  退后
Sandy, stand back
我警告你
I'm warning ya
好  我警告过你了
Okay, I warned ya
你赢了吗
Did you win?
嗨  海绵宝宝
Hi, SpongeBob
坏蛋丹                   钉子头拉里
好吧  海绵宝宝
Okay, SpongeBob
你来当坏蛋丹
you can be Dirty Dan
我只想当派大星
I just want to be Patrick
我们快出去
Let's get out of here
免得珊迪又突然醒过来
before Sandy wakes up again
抱歉  派大星
Sorry, Patrick
门特别滑
but the door is slippery
冻住了
It's frozen shut
我来试试看
Let me have a try
芝麻开门
Open, Sesame
我已经尽力了
Well, I've done all I can do
那我们就被困在这了
Then we're stuck in here
大门解冻才能出去
until the door thaws
得等到春天
in spring
真见鬼
Barnacles
春天到了吗
Is it spring yet?
没
N-n-no
我都冷得打哆嗦了
I'm so c-c-cold that I'm shivering
我都冷得能拿鼻涕
I-I'm so cold that I can use my nose drippings
当筷子用了
as a pair of chopsticks
我冷得
I-I'm so c-cold that
都打哆嗦了
I'm shivering
也许我们该烧个火
Maybe we should build a fire
有了
I've got it
烧珊迪树上的树皮好了
We'll burn the bark from Sandy's tree
等我把你解决了
You're gonna be wearing an iron lung
你必戴人工呼吸器  钉子头
when I'm through with you, Pinhead
火生不起来  派大星
The fire's not going to happen, Patrick
我不明白
I don't get it
珊迪每年咋撑得过这么恶劣的情况
How does Sandy
survive these intense conditions every year?
可能因为是她直接无视了
Maybe she just ignores it
可能
Maybe
可能因为她的毛
Maybe it's her fur
对了
Yeah
快看那堆暖和的毛
Look at all that warm, toasty fur
就好像是长毛的金矿
It's like a gold mine, but with fur
小心
Carefully
动作快啊
Come on, do it
我都冷死了
I'm freezing here
好了好了
All right, all right
稍安勿躁
hang on a second
这么多应该够吧
That should be enough, right?
海绵宝宝  我是大男人
Sponge, I'm a big man
特别大个的男人
A big, big man
看来我一生已经过完了
Well, I guess I've lived a full life
你扒得也太慢了
This is taking too long
我现在就要温暖
I want the warm now
派大星  不要
Pat, no
派大星  你疯了吗
Pat, are you crazy?
不
No
我暖和了
I'm warm
那卷胶带给我看看
Let me see that roll of tape
她的毛真的好给力
Man, that fur really hits the spot
胳肢窝再也不会受冻了
No more frozen armpits
一字眉山羊胡组合大有奇效
And this eyebrow/goatee combo works like a charm
这是我们最好的主意
This the best idea we've ever had
没错
You said it
我准备好度过最久最冷的冬天了
I'm ready for the longest, coldest winter ever
放马过来
Bring it on
春天了
Spring?
已经春天了
Spring already
真该死
Tartar sauce
锁还冻着
The lock is still frozen
我等不及要出去暖暖身上的毛了
I sure can't wait to get outside and warm my fur
看啊  是海绵宝宝跟派大星
Oh, look, it's SpongeBob and Patrick
你们好
Hi, guys
没事  珊迪
It's okay, Sandy
松鼠型脱毛
Squirrel pattern baldness
在小型哺乳动物当中很常见
is quite common in small mammals
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
派大星
Patrick
你放心  珊迪
Don't worry, Sandy
我们会帮你解决的
We've got you covered
盖 好
要不要再来点柠檬水
More lemonade, boys?
谢谢珊迪
Thanks, Sandy
春天真美好
Spring sure is lovely
被抛弃
导演
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
分镜总监
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
找到你了  小蜗
I've got you now, Gary
抓到了  你当鬼
Tag, you're it
小蜗肯定不会发现我在这
Gary will never find me here
抓到了
Tag
现在我当鬼
Now I'm it
嗨  海绵宝宝
Hi, SpongeBob
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我跟小蜗在玩抓人游戏
Gary and I are playing tag
要一起来玩吗
You want to join us?
好啊  当然要
Oh, boy, would I?
好
Okay
抓到了
Tag
你当鬼
you're it
我当鬼
I'm it
抓到了  你当鬼
Tag, you're it
我赢了
I win
小蜗怎么了
What's with Gary?
声音跟汽船似的
He sounds like a motorboat
那只是蜗牛表示喜欢的方式
That's just a snail's way of saying he likes you
好痒
Tickles
看来现在
Well, I guess it's time
我跟小蜗该走了
for me and the Gar Bear to get going
来吧  小蜗
Come on, Gary
天啊  我等不及要去睡觉了
Boy, I can't wait to hit the hay
你呢  小蜗
How about you, Gary?
小蜗
Gary?
刷刷刷
Brush, brush, brush
派大星  你看到小蜗了吗
Hey, Patrick, have you seen Gary?
刷刷刷
Brush, brush, brush
到处都要刷
Brushing everywhere
没
Nope
小蜗在这
Here he is
来吧  小蜗
Come on, Gary
让派大星好好睡觉
We've got to let Patrick go to sleep
我不介意  海绵宝宝
I don't mind, SpongeBob
说实话
In fact
不然你今晚就让小蜗来我家睡好了
why don't you let Gary sleep over at my house tonight?
真是个好办法
That's a great idea
来过夜  好棒
A sleep-over, oh, boy
一定会特别棒的  小蜗
This is going to be great, Gary
可以通宵看恐怖电影
We can stay up till dawn and watch scary movies
吃爆米花  玩桌游
and eat popcorn and play board games
好棒
This is great
我全海洋最好的两个朋友一起过夜
My two best friends in the whole sea having a sleep-over
然后一起搭纸牌屋
And then we'll make a house of cards
然后一起看漫画
and then we'll read some comic books
好  你们好好去玩
Okay, you guys have a good time
明天再见
I'll see you tomorrow
我醒了
I'm awake
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
昨天过夜怎么样
Hey, guys, how was the sleep-over?
可棒了  海绵宝宝
Great, SpongeBob
看好了
Watch this
我走到哪小蜗就跟到哪
No matter where I go, Gary follows
看到没
See?
来吧  小蜗
Come on, Gary
快来抓
Try and catch
我
me
是不是很棒啊  小蜗
Isn't this great, Gary?
我到处跑  你来追我
Me running around and you chasing me
你都没在追我
You're not chasing me
来吧  小蜗
Come on, Gary
我们换另外一个游戏玩
Let's go play a different game
小心  我就在你前面
Look out, I'm right in front of you
我是怎么了
What's wrong with me?
冒犯到人家了吗
Do I offend?
小蜗
Hey, Gary
小蜗你看
Gary, look
是你最爱的球
It's your favorite ball
小蜗
Hey, Gary
你看
Look
蜗薄荷
Snail-nip
救命
Help
小蜗  救命
Gary, help
救救我
Help me
我的海神王啊
Merciful Neptune
我关窗夹到头了
I closed the window on my head
好了  都够了
All right, that's it
小蜗  不准你再胡闹了
Gary, you stop this foolishness right now
蜗牛小蜗  我问话你就必须回话
Gary the Snail, answer me when I'm talking to you
好
Okay
到此为止
that's it, mister
你马上跟我回家
You are coming home with me right this instant
跟派大星说再见  小蜗
Say good-bye to Patrick, Gary
慢着  生气爸妈宝宝
Hold it right there, DadMom AngryPants
你那是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
不知道
I don't know
但我知道小蜗心里清楚要跟谁走
But I do know Gary knows who he wants to go with
建议你现在给我放下小蜗
Now, I suggest you put him down
由小蜗自己来选择
and let him choose
好  但我想提醒一下小蜗
Fine, but I would like to remind him
是谁整天供小蜗吃供小蜗住
who it was that fed him and housed him
在小蜗生病时守在小蜗床边
and sat at his bedside when he was sick
还在眼睛疼的时候帮忙按摩眼柄
and massaged his eyestalks when his eyes were sore
好  小蜗
Okay, Gary
去证明给他看
go ahead, show him
好  小蜗
Okay, Gary
来我这边
come to me
快啊快啊  小蜗
Come on, come on, Gary
快啊
Come on
到这来  小蜗
come here, Gary
走错了  小蜗
Wrong way, Gary
小蜗  快调头
G-Gary, turn around
小蜗  调头
Gary, turn around
小蜗  不
Gary, no
小蜗  不不不
Gary, no, no, no
别过去  小蜗
No, don't do it, Gary
不  小蜗
No, Gary
好好好
Well, well, well
看来答案揭晓了
I guess that answers that question
再见  海绵宝宝
So long, SpongeBob
我跟小蜗有事要做
Gary and me got stuff to do
好  行
Okay, fine
如果你就这样谢我
If that's the way you want to thank me
谢我为你做的一切
for all that I've done
小蜗
看来你不肯回来了  小蜗
I guess you're not coming back, Gary
我不需要小蜗
I don't need Gary
我再找一只宠物好了
I'll just find another pet
好  肯定比小蜗强
Yeah, it will be better than Gary
我要养一只
I'm going to get a pet
不会跟我最好的朋友跑路的宠物
who won't go off with my best friend
你们好
Hi, guys
跟我的新朋友雷克斯打个招呼
Say hello to my new pal Rex
它不仅忠诚
Not only is he loyal
还会听我话做动作
but he knows tricks, too
好好看好好学
Watch and learn
坐下  雷克斯
Sit, Rex, sit
翻滚  雷克斯
Roll over, Rex, roll over
不要动  雷克斯
Now stay, Rex, stay
乖虫虫  雷克斯
Good boy, Rex
谁是乖虫虫
Who's a good boy?
很高兴我们分道扬镳了  小蜗
I'm sure glad we went our separate ways, Gary
虫子才是适合我的宠物
A worm really is the pet for me
忠诚  又值得信任
So loyal, so trusting
在我身边不离不弃
Always by my side
公交站
谁稀罕虫子啊
Who needs worms anyway?
欢迎到家  新任好朋友
Welcome home, newest best friend
出来吧  别害羞
Come on out, don't be shy
你让我想起了我曾经认识过的某位
You remind me of someone I once knew
这位的名字
A certain someone whose name
不能在这个家里说出来
will not be mentioned in this household
走吧  我来带你参观一下
Come on, let me show you around
小拉
Larry
现在  小拉
And now, Larry
为你献上晚餐时间
I present to you dinner time
哒哒
Ta-da
小拉
用餐愉快  小拉
Bon appétit, Larry
好吧
Okay
等会再吃
maybe later
你就在这睡觉  小拉
This is where you sleep, Larry
我在那睡
That's where I
那就让你睡那边
I guess you can sleep there
我就睡这下面好了
I'll sleep down here
晚安了  小拉
Well, goodnight, Larry
小拉
Larry
想听笑话吗
Want to hear a joke?
小蜗以前特别爱这条笑话
Gary used to love this one
船上的蜗牛叫什么
What do you call a snail on a ship?
蜗手
A snailor
没听懂吗  小拉
Don't you get it, Larry
蜗
A
蜗手
a snailor
天啊  小拉跟小蜗区别太大了
Gosh, Larry sure is different than Gary
小蜗和小拉
And Gary and Larry
跟小杰的区别非常大
are real different than Jerry
小蜗  你为什么要离我而去
Gary, why did you have to go?
为什么  小蜗
Why, Gary
为什么
why?
为什么  为什么
Why, why?
小蜗
Gary?
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
你好  派大星
Hello, Patrick
你好
Hello
小蜗
Gary
请问可不可以
Would it be all right
让我和小蜗在这洗衣服
if Gary and I did some laundry over here?
洗衣服
Laundry?
我们以前常常洗衣服
But we used to do laundry
还有
And, uh
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
能借点肥皂用吗
Could we borrow some soap?
肥皂
Soap?
我们以前常常用肥皂
But we used to use soap
你想要
Do you want
清香型还是耐
fresh scent or heavy
清香型
耐用型
用
du
要来了
Here it comes
耐用
Duty
重 任
小蜗
Gary
求你回来吧  小蜗
Please come back, Gary
快回家吧
Please come home
没了你我就废了
I'm a wreck without you
有了
I know
如果你回来
If you come back
就定一条不准定规矩的规矩
there will be a no-rules rule
你想什么时候玩什么东西都可以
You can do whatever you want when you want
想扒沙发可以使劲扒
If you feel like ripping up the sofa, rip it up
至于砂盆
And the litter box?
用不着了
Forget about it
全世界就是你的砂盆
The world is your litter box
而且你再也不用
And you don't have to
等着我来喂你了
wait around for me to feed you anymore
冰箱全天候随便开
24-hour fridge access
连碗都可以不用拿了
And you don't even have to use a bowl
我知道你有多喜欢
I know how much you like
我珍贵的章鱼哥浮木雕
my prized driftwood carving of Squidward
把它当抓板放心给你抓
Well, think of it as your own personal scratching post
怎么样  小蜗
What do you think, Gary?
有不有趣  小蜗
Won't it be fun, Gary?
太可悲了
How pathetic
小蜗
Gary
对不起  海绵宝宝
I'm sorry, SpongeBob
小蜗现在只跟我走
but Gary's with me now
你机会用完了  也失败了
You had your chance and you failed
不能再活在过去了
You have to stop living in the past
面对现实吧  海绵宝宝
Face it, SpongeBob
你只会伤害到你自己
You're only hurting yourself
这就是小蜗想要的
It's what Gary wants
而小蜗想要的  就是我
and what Gary wants, is me
对吧  小蜗
Right, Gary?
它只喜欢我的短裤
He only liked me for my shorts
不对  派大星
No, Patrick
小蜗想要你口袋里的饼干
He wanted the cookie in your pocket
小蜗
G-G-Gary?
小蜗  我就知道你不会抛弃我
Gary, I knew you'd never leave me
我们去遛遛吧  兄弟
Let's go for a walk, pal
小蜗
Gary?
我们先前经历的一切明明很特别
I thought what we had was special